# Teten Nugraha

Bandung, West Java, Indonesia



teten.nugraha18@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/teten-nugraha

## **Summary**

I am a software engineer with over 7 years' experience working on complex software development initiatives. I'm passionate about software development and I'm looking forward to getting to work on new projects in the near future.

Currently employed as a Product engineer at Gopaylater (Part of Goto Financial Group) and Previously as Senior Software Engineer at MokaPOS, I manage projects to develop, maintain and improve paylater systems. I

While employed in this role, I was successful break monolith system written with Ruby on Rails and Java to be Java Microservices with WebMVC and Webflux and Kotlin.

In my spare time, I enjoy writing some articles and tweeting about programming

Feel free to send me a message if you would like to know more about me. I am always eager to hear from others and expand my network on LinkedIn.

Specialties: Java, Spring Boot, Go Language, Kafka, Postgresql, Docker & Kubernetes

## **Experience**

## **Product Engineer (Gopaylater)**

GoTo Financial

Mar 2023 - Present (7 months)

- Identify, prioritize and execute tasks in the software development life cycle
- Develop tools and applications by producing clean, efficient code
- Review and debug code
- Document development phases and monitor systems
- Mentor Software Engineers to allow for skill/knowledge development through advice, coaching, and training opportunities.

#### Stacks:

- Java 17
- Java & Kotlin for Backend
- Spring MVC & Webflux
- Kafka
- Grpc
- Aerospike
- Kubernetes

## Software Engineer (Commerce Enablement)

GoTo Financial

Nov 2021 - Feb 2023 (1 year 4 months)

- Migrating some Rails service to Java Service
- Maintain code
- Code Review
- Update Kong Gateway Plugin
- Maintenance Spring Boot Version
- Monitoring Services using New Relic, Datadog, Grafana
- SCRUM

#### Stacks:

- Kubernetes
- Java Spring Boot MVC
- Kafka and Kafka Stream
- NodeJS



#### DevOps Engineer (Weekend Volunteer for Non Profit Org.)

#### PP Pemuda Persis

Aug 2022 - Jan 2023 (6 months)

- Setup Sonarqube for quality code
- Setup Gitlab CICD
- Deploy to Droplet DO
- Maintenance docker images using aws ecr

## 📵 Software Engineer

#### Allianz Indonesia

Jan 2019 - Oct 2021 (2 years 10 months)

As a software engineer at Allianz Indonesia especially on the Backend team, I am tasked with providing several related REST APIs:

- Store and manage sales activity data
- View sales sales results
- Provide data on sales achievement dashboard
- Provide data on contest selling
- Provides data for all policies
- Collaborates with team about Backlog refinement
- Code Review and pair programming
- Maintain CI/CD Jenkins Pipeline integrate with Openshift

I also use several technologies for that, namely:

- Spring Boot
- OpenJDK 11
- Microservices Architecture
- Oracle DB
- PostgreSQL
- Apache Kafka
- Openshift
- Docker
- Jenkins

- Sonarqube
- Event Driven
- Checkmark
- Fortify

## iResearch Manager

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018 (1 year)

At RAD Research Company, I am tasked with providing solution services regarding research results that previously used a Powerpoint manual and changed using Realtime Web Analytic. I have several roles including:

1. as a Product Engineer

I made a design starting from a wireframe, a mockup which later will be delivered to the client for review first and will also be forwarded to the Frontend Engineer to start building the product.

2. as Software Engineer

I created several responses which later will be used by me and the backend team to provide data as designed.

I also use several technologies for that, namely:

- Balsamic Mockup
- Adobe XD
- React and Redux
- Laravel
- Nodejs Express
- MySQL
- Ubuntu 18
- Bootstrap UI
- NodeJS

## Associate iResearch Manager

Dec 2016 - Dec 2017 (1 year 1 month)

## Full Stack Engineer

Dec 2015 - Dec 2016 (1 year 1 month)

## 矮 Java Developer

PT Intek Sarana Sejahtera

Sep 2012 - Dec 2015 (3 years 4 months)

In this company I worked on several projects, namely creating a Knowledge Management System, Data Distribution Unit, and Combat Management System. All of them are used for military purposes.

The technology used is:

- OpenJDK
- Hibernate
- MySQL
- Ubuntu
- Java 2D
- OpenSplice Messaging
- Netbeans

- Maven

#### Non-permanent Lecture

Universitas Komputer Indonesia

Aug 2013 - Jan 2014 (6 months)

I taught at UNIKOM for one semester with a subject, namely Java Programming 3 which includes:

- Netbeans
- JDK
- Hibernate
- JasperReport
- MySQL

#### **Assistant Professor**

Universitas Komputer Indonesia Aug 2009 - Aug 2012 (3 years 1 month)

## **Intershipp Programmer**

bank bjb Jul 2010 - Oct 2010 (4 months) PHP, Java, XAMP,MySQL

#### **Education**

## **Universitas Komputer Indonesia**

Sarjana Komputer, Sistem Informasi 2008 - 2012

#### **Licenses & Certifications**

- AWS Technical Essentials Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials Day Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Developing on AWS Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- in Building Java Microservices with gRPC LinkedIn
- in Java Memory Management LinkedIn
- Software Architecture: Domain-Driven Design LinkedIn
- in Level Up: Advanced SQL LinkedIn

- in Functional Programming with Java LinkedIn
- in Applied Concurrency in Go LinkedIn

#### **Skills**

Reactive Programming • Go (Programming Language) • Functional Programming • REST API • Spring Boot • Microservices • Manajemen Proyek • Pengembangan Software • Mean Stack • LAMP

#### **Honors & Awards**

Mahasiswa - Rektor Universitas Komputer Indonesia Jul 2012

Mahasiswa Terbaik ke-2 se jurusan Sistem Informasi Komputer Indonesia